Guide to the Irving Rosenthal Papers
Department of Special Collections
- Series II. CORRESPONDENCE
  - Huncke, Herbert, 1959-1973, 12.5-16.4.
    - Huncke, 1961-1962, Huncke-Rosenthal correspondence: extensive correspondence; includes transcripts of "Forty Thieves" and "Argument between Huncke and Irving"; artwork, notes, and greeting card., 12.5.
    - Huncke, 1965-1968, Huncke-Rosenthal correspondence: extensive correspondence; includes correspondence regarding Huncke's Ching; flyer for Huncke's Journal (1965) and postcards., 12.6.
    - Huncke, 1959-1960, other correspondence: extensive correspondence; includes correspondence with Mollie Collins, Allen Ginsberg, Peter Orlovsky, Jack Kerouac, et al.; telegram, notes, postcards, receipts, and legal papers., 12.7.
    - Huncke, 1961, other correspondence: extensive correspondence; includes correspondence with Janine Pommy, Howard Schulman, et al.; artwork by Arnold Levin and postcards., 12.8.
    - Huncke, 1961, other correspondence: extensive correspondence; includes correspondence with Elizabeth Sutherland, Janine Pommy, et al.; includes artwork by Janine Pommy and Arnold Levin., 12.9.
    - Huncke, 1961-1966, miscellaneous manuscripts and typescripts: includes manuscripts and notes for portions of Huncke's Ching, including "Burroughs," "Herbert E. Huncke/Hunks/H.E.H.," and others., 12.10.
    - Huncke, 1966-1967, miscellaneous manuscripts and typescripts: includes manuscripts, "Bill Burroughs, Wm. S. Burroughs, Alias Bull Lee" and others; also includes typescript, "The Mysterious He" and Huncke's first notes on Huncke's Ching., 13.1.
    - Huncke, Herbert, 1967, miscellaneous manuscripts and typescripts: includes artwork by Huncke and correspondence., 13.2.
    - Huncke, 1963-1965: loose typescripts, 13.3.
    - Huncke, 1965: typescript of Huncke's Journal, 13.4.
    - Huncke, 1966: "Green Notebook" typescripts, 13.5.
    - Huncke, 1966: typescripts of "Burroughs" and "Bill Burroughs, Wm. S. Burroughs, Alias Bull Lee", 13.6.
    - Huncke, ca. 1966: compilation of all Huncke's typescripts through 1966 (Rosenthal notes that this is the most complete set; 20 pages are missing); includes some pieces published in Huncke's Journal and many pieces included in Huncke's Ching, as well as additional fragments and untitled pieces. (3 folders), 14.1-14.3.
    - Huncke, ca. 1966: compilation of all Huncke's typescripts through 1966 (Rosenthal notes that this is a less complete set; around 50 pages are missing); includes some pieces published in Huncke's Journal and many pieces included in Huncke's Ching, as well as additional fragments and untitled pieces. (2 folders), 14.4-14.5.
    - Huncke, 1966-1967: contains index cards listing information about Huncke's manuscripts., 15.1.
    - Huncke, 1966-1967: loose typescripts (5 folders), 15.2-15.6
    - Huncke, 1967: contains the typescript of Huncke's Ching offered to Grove Press. (2 folders), 16.1-16.2.
    - Huncke, 1973: contains duplicate of restored Huncke's Ching typescript. (2 folders), 16.3-16.4.
  - Hutchins, Robert, 1958-1959: correspondence, 17.1.
  - Itkin, Michael, 1966-1969: letter, booklet, flyer, greeting card, 17.2.
  - Johnson, Ray, 1961-1995: correspondence, flyers, 17.3
  - Jones, LeRoi, 1960-1966: correspondence; includes postcard, clipping, typescript of "Cuba Libra" published in Kulcher 2 (1960)., 17.4
    Also known as Baraka, Imamu Amiri.
  - Karo, George and Helene, 1951-1976: correspondence; includes Rosenthal's notes and exams for George Karo's ancient art and archeology course., 17.5.
  - Kerouac, Jack, Lucien Midnight, 1958: manuscript cover and copies of typescript, 17.6.
  - Kerouac, Jack, 1958-1959: extensive correspondence; includes telegram, postcards, clipping, note from Allen Ginsberg and Peter Orlovsky to Rosenthal, manuscript cover for Old Angel Midnight., 17.7.
    See also Big Table, folder # 33.4, for Old Angel Midnight typescript
  - Keys, Anthony, 1989-1990: letters, 17.8.
  - Koch, Helene L., 1957-1961: letters, 17.9.
  - Kokkinen, Eila, 1959-1964: extensive correspondence; includes resume, postcards, telegrams, notes, photographs., 17.10.
  - Kokkinen, Eila, 1965-2000: extensive correspondence; includes letters regarding personal issues such as health and friendships, as well as references to Herbert Huncke's memorial service, Allen Ginsberg's death, and other events., 17.11.
  - Koller, James, 1959-1960: correspondence, 17.12.
  - Kray, Betty, 1958: correspondence, 17.13.
  - Kreplick, Joseph and Ruth, 1960: correspondence; includes flyer., 18.1.
  - Kroll, Michael, 1957-1958: correspondence; includes postcards., 18.2.
  - Kyger, Joanne, 1968-1981: letters, postcard, 18.3.
  - Lamantia, Philip, 1961-1964: correspondence; includes typescript by Raphael Kohler., 18.4.
  - LaVigne, Robert, 1967-1982: correspondence; includes artwork., 18.5.
  - LaVigne, Robert, ca. 1970: "Round Yellow," print, no.1, Tube 39.
  - Lee, Sondra, 1967: typescript of poems for Glamorous Novelties., 18.6.
  - Levin Arnold, 1960-1961: correspondence; includes artwork., 18.7.
  - Lionni, Paolo, 1966: typescripts, forms, 18.8.
  - Lowell, James, 1967-1969: letters, 18.9.
  - Mailer, Norman, 1961: letters, 18.10.
  - Markman, Joel, 1963-1966: letters, photographs, 18.11.
  - Marpol, Stephen, 1964-1968: photographs, letter, postcard, 18.12.
  - Marshall, Edward, 1955-1973, 18.13-21.9.
    - Marshall, 1955-1961: extensive correspondence; includes typescripts, postcards, photographs., 18.13.
    - Marshall, 1962-1973: extensive correspondence; includes notes, typescripts, pamphlets., 18.14.
    - Marshall, 1967: printing materials for Transit Glory; drafts, notes, mock-ups, artwork, 18.15.
    - Marshall, 1967: Transit Glory, published by Carp and Whitefish with drawings by William Heine., 18.16.
    - Marshall, ca. 1970: printing materials for unpublished book; includes notes, mock-ups, artwork, table of contents., 18.17.
    - Marshall, 1972: printing materials for Pole Volt; includes drafts, notes, mock-ups, artwork., 18.18.
    - Marshall, 1972: edited poems on index cards, poems selected and rejected for Pole Volt, 19.1.
    - Marshall, 1972: proofs for Pole Volt (3 folders), 19.2-19.4.
    - Marshall, 1972: book spine pattern jig for Pole Volt, Flat Box 20.
    - Marshall, 1972: bound dummy for Pole Volt, 21.1.
    - Marshall, 1972: unbound dummies for Pole Volt, 21.2.
    - Marshall, Doris Nieder, no date: Nieder's collations of "Leave the Word Alone" and "How Deep is Thy Love", 21.3.
    - Marshall, Black Mountain Review, 1957: autumn issue, 21.4.
    - Marshall, Yugan, 1959-1961: nos. 4 and 7, 21.5.
    - Marshall, Measure, 1962: no. 3, 21.6.
    - Marshall, Fuck You: A Magazine for the Arts, 1962: vol. 1, no. 5, 21.7.
    - Marshall, 1967: The Great Society, 21.8.
    - Marshall, M.E.A.L, 1970: vol. 2, no. 2, 21.9.
  - Matson, Clive, ca. 1962-1984: correspondence; includes typescripts, postcards, broadsides, flyer., 21.10.
  - McClure, Michael, 1957-1961: extensive correspondence; includes correspondence with Paul Carroll and others; also typescripts, postcards, broadside, drawing., 22.1.
  - McClure, Michael, 1962: extensive correspondence; includes typescripts of Thirteen Mad Sonnets, The Cigar, others; photograph of McClure ca. 1962., 22.2.
  - McClure, Michael, 1963-1978: extensive correspondence; includes McClure's comments on Sheeper, notes, postcards, "Herakles," poem dedicated to Rosenthal., 22.3.
  - McGilvery, Lawrence, 1952-2000: letter, note, greeting cards, 22.4.
  - McLeod, Anthony, 1953-1954: letters, 22.5.
  - McLeod, Daniel, 1953-1955: letters, 22.6.
  - McReynolds, David, 1959: letters, 22.7.
  - Meeker, Marilynn, 1960-1961: letters, 22.8.
  - Mekas, Jonas, 1959-1961: letters, 22.9.
  - Meltzer, David, 1962: letter, 22.10.
  - Millward, Pamela, 1967: typescripts, 22.11.
  - Milne, Kay, 1951-1954: letters, postcards, greeting card, 22.12.
  - Mondadori, Fabrizio, 1962: letters, 22.13.
  - Montez, Mario, 1966-1967: flyers, poster, photograph, 22.14.
  - Moraft, Barbara, 1959-1961: letters, telegram, 22.15.
  - Morris, Charles and Ruth, 1952-1958: correspondence; includes greeting card, postcard, 22.16.
  - Morris, William, 1959-1960: postcard, letter, flyer, photograph, 22.17.
  - Nakamura, Utaemon VI, 1960-2001: letters, photographs, obituaries, 22.18.
  - Neide, Peter, 1962-1965: extensive correspondence; mostly letters from Neide to Leo Skir; also includes receipts., 22.19.
  - Neidorf, Mary, 1953-1960: letters, greeting cards, postcards, photographs, 22.20.
  - Nelson, Gareth, 1958-1960: correspondence; includes postcards, 22.21.
  - Neugarten, Bernice, 1957: letters, 22.22.
  - Nichols, Clinton, 1959-1960: letters, postcards, typescripts, note, 22.23.
  - Nicoletti, Richard, 1967: typescripts, drawings, note, 22.24.
  - Nieder, Doris, 1959: correspondence, 22.25.
  - Olson, Charles, 1959-1960: typescripts, letters, note, 22.26.
  - Ong, Nancy, 1951-1952: letters, greeting card, 22.27.
  - Oppenheimer, Joel, 1958: letters, typescripts, 22.28.
  - Orlovsky, Marie, 1961: letters, note, 22.29.
  - Orlovsky, Peter, 1959-1978: correspondence; includes postcards., 22.30.
  - Page, Marjorie, 1956-1959: correspondence; includes postcards and clipping., 23.1.
  - Persky, Stan, 1960-1961: letters, 23.2.
  - Pitschel, Barbara, 1957-1968: correspondence; includes postcards., 23.3.
  - Pitschel, Roland, 1958-1959: letters, telegram, postcard, 23.4.
  - Plimpton, George, 1964-1965: letters, 23.5.
  - Plymell, Charles, 1967: typescript for Glamorous Novelties, 23.6.
  - Podell, Albert, 1958-1961: extensive correspondence; includes postcards, telegrams, clippings., 23.7.
  - Pommy, Janine, 1961-1967: notes, typescript, 23.8.
  - Rechy, John, 1959-1962: correspondence; includes clippings., 23.9.
  - Rexroth, Kenneth, 1958: letter, 23.10.
  - Richkin, Robert, 1967-1969: galley proof, letters, typescript, manuscript, 23.11.
  - Riesman, David, 1957-1958: correspondence, 23.12.
  - Rogers, Carl, 1952-1956: correspondence; includes notes and copy of research proposal., 23.13.
  - Rogers Pugh, Harriet, 1955-1957: letters, postcard, greeting card, 23.14.
  - Romagnolo, Fred, 1949-1959: extensive correspondence; includes postcards, telegram, greeting cards, photographs., 23.15.
  - Rosenthal, Belle and Sidney (Rosenthal's parents), 1921-1982: correspondence; includes Sidney's operator's license, telegram, greeting cards, copy of clipping, letter from Belle to Allen Ginsberg, copy of Belle's will., 23.16.
  - Safro, Malka, 1960-1961: letters, postcards, 23.17.
  - Sanders, Edward, 1950-1957: extensive correspondence, 23.18.
  - Sanders, Melvin, 1951-1963: extensive correspondence; includes postcards, greeting card, telegrams., 23.19.
  - Schleifer, Marc, 1958-1962: extensive correspondence; includes broadside, telegrams, typescript, photograph, galley proofs, poster., 24.1.
  - Schleifer, Marc, 1962-1982: extensive correspondence; includes clippings, flyers, photographs., 24.2.
  - Schleifer, Marc, poetry reading project, 1959: correspondence; includes notes, telegrams, flyer, postcard., 24.3.
  - Schleifer, Marc, letters from Marian Zazeela, 1958-1962; extensive correspondence includes typescripts, photographs, slides, The Monthly Review, vol. 13, nos. 3 and 4 (1961)., 24.4.
  - Schleifer, Marc, letters to Marian Zazeela, 1961-1962: extensive correspondence; includes notes., 24.5.
  - Schlesinger, Arthur, 1958-1961: letters, 24.6.
  - Schulman, Howard, 1959-1962: extensive correspondence; includes postcards, typescripts, Pa'lante, no.1 (1962)., 24.7.
  - Schulman, Howard, 1962-1985: extensive correspondence; includes flyer, telegram, postcards, typescript., 24.8.
  - Skir, Leo, 1962-1969: extensive correspondence; includes typescripts for memoir, postcards, notes, photographs (contact sheet)., 24.9.
  - Smalakis, Laura, 1954-1958: correspondence; includes postcards, greeting cards, 24.10.
  - Smith, Jack, 1958-1996, 25.1-30.3
    - Smith, 1961: correspondence; includes typescript transcriptions of taped conversations between Smith, Rosenthal, Herbert Huncke, others; also notes, membership card., 25.1.
    - Smith, 1962: correspondence; includes copies of letters from Smith to David Gurin; also notes and Scene, vol. 8, no. 2., 25.2.
    - Smith, 1963-1975: extensive correspondence; includes copy of "Rehearsal for the Destruction of Atlantis"; also clippings, flyers, notes, Film-Makers Cooperative catalogue (1963), inscribed to Rosenthal., 25.3.
    - Smith, 1977-1989: extensive correspondence; includes clippings, notes, flyers, postcards, photograph., 25.4.
    - Smith, 1989-1996: letters, notes, clippings, obituaries, Rosenthal's phone interviews with Jack Smith's sister, Mary Sue Slater, 25.5.
    - Smith, 1959: mounted photograph of Jerry Sims, 25.6.
    - Smith, photographs 1960: photographs of Smith, one on collage, 25.7.
    - Smith, contact sheets, 1960-1961: contact sheets for photo shoots picturing Rene Rivera (Mario Montez), Marian Zazeela, et al., some with tape to indicate cropping and framing, 25.8.
    - Smith, photographs, 1961: photographs and negatives of Rosenthal and Reese Haire, 25.9.
    - Smith, photographs, ca. 1959-1966: black and white photographs of Mario Montez, Rosenthal, Reese Haire, Isabel Eberstadt, et al., Flat Box 26.1.
    - Smith, mounted photograph, ca. 1958: color photograph of two costumed figures in Lincoln Center rubble., Flat Box 26.2.
    - Smith, mounted photograph, ca. 1958: color photograph of costumed figure leaning on a platter., Flat Box 26.3.
    - Smith, Sheeper photographs, 1967: photographs of Rosenthal for Sheeper dust jacket; note by Rosenthal describes re-touching of photographs, 25.10.
    - Smith, artwork and ephemera, ca. 1961-1966: drawings, cartoons, booklets, flyers; includes flyer for Flaming Creatures, negative of Mario Montez., 25.11.
    - Smith, The Beautiful Book, 1962: booklet with photos by Smith, 25.12.
    - Smith, artwork and ephemera, ca. 1966-1970: drawings and designs for Glamorous Novelties, Sheeper, Marbels from Cockaroch Morseleum, others; also includes cartoons and flyers., 25.13.
    - Smith, Dreamweapon, 1962: booklet by Angus Maclise with Smith photographs printed on paper; poster originally folded into booklet., Flat Box 27.1.
    - Smith, press plates, 1966-1968: aluminum press plates for Hollow Prescenium Mountain, No President, and business card., Flat Box 27.2.
    - Smith, manila folder project, 1967: artwork on manila folders, Flat Box 27.3.
    - Smith, Avalanche, 1974: art magazine with spread by Smith, Flat Box 27.4.
    - Smith, posters, 1976-1984: posters for Smith's productions; includes The Secret of Rented Island, I was a Male Yvonne de Carlo, others., Flat Box 27.5.
    - Smith, Art-Rite, 1975-1978: nos. 11, 12 (1975-1976); includes short article on Jack Smith, "American Tourister"; no. 19 (1978); includes text and art by Smith, "Capitalism of Lotusland.", 25.14.
    - Smith, ca. 1961: costume garment, Flat Box 28.
    - Smith, ca. 1961: costume garments; sent to Rosenthal after Smith's death., Flat Box 29.
    - Smith, publicity packet, 1987: copies of press clippings and flyers; includes draft of cover note and note by Jeanette Szudy., 30.1.
    - Smith, 1988: typescript dissertation chapter on Smith by Uzi Parnes, 30.2.
    - Smith, 1996: typescript essay on Smith by Lawrence Rinder; includes letter to Rosenthal., 30.3.
  - Snyder, Gary, 1958: letters, 30.4.
  - Solomon, Carl, 1960: letter, note, 30.5.
  - Solomon, Freude and Norman: 1961-1962: correspondence; includes postcards, notes, unopened letter from Freude to Elise Cowan (opened in 2008 during processing)., 30.6.
  - Sourelis, Stan, 1959: letters, postcard, greeting card, 30.7.
  - Spellman, A. B., 1960: typescript of poem published in Kulcher 2., 30.8.
  - Standal, Stanley, 1953-1961: extensive correspondence; includes postcards, greeting cards, photographs, portion of Standal's dissertation., 30.9.
  - Stubenhaus, Abbe, 1967-1974: letters, typescripts, postcards, wedding prayer book, 30.10.
  - Sturz, Herbert, 1951-1983: extensive correspondence; includes postcards, greeting cards., 30.11.
  - Sutherland, Elizabeth, 1961: letters, 30.12.
  - Suzuki, D.T., 1958: typescript, "Rinzai on Zen", 30.13.
  - Taylor, Simon Watson, 1959: greeting card, note, postcard, 30.14.
  - Tedesco, Claudia, 1969-1986: letters, postcards, greeting cards, photographs, 30.15.
  - Turnbull, Gael, 1958: letter, 30.16.
  - Usdansky, George, 1955-1960: extensive correspondence; includes postcards, clippings, audograph disc., 30.17.
  - Waring, James, 1960-1961: letter, note, typescript, 30.18.
  - Whalen, Philip, 1958-2002: extensive correspondence; includes postcards, notes, artwork, obituaries., 31.1.
  - Whalen, Philip, A Commentary, 1960: one page poster-sized manuscript, 3.3.
  - Whalen, Philip, Invention of the Letter, 1966: manuscript of hand-drawn book and final copy for reproduction, 31.2.
  - Whalen, Philip, Invention of the Letter, 1967: copies of uncut pages, 31.3.
  - Whalen, Philip, Winning His Way, 1967: manuscript of hand-drawn book with cover letter, 31.4.
  - Whalen, Philip, Winning His Way, 1982-1983: pre-press drawings, plates, and proofs, 3.4.
  - Whiteman, Ruth, 1954: letter, postcard, notes, 31.5.
  - Wieners, John, 1959-1961: extensive correspondence; includes letters to Freude Solomon and others; also manuscripts, notes, telegram, clippings., 31.6.
  - Wieners, John, 1961-2002: extensive correspondence; includes letters to Freude Solomon and others; also manuscript, flyers, clippings, greeting cards, Zarza, April, 1961, Measure, no. 3, 1962, "In Memoriam John Wieners," 2002., 31.7.
  - Williams, Jonathan, 1958-1978: letters, postcards, greeting cards, newsletter, 31.8.
  - Yarborough, Ernest, 1957: photocopy of postcard, greeting card, 31.9.
  - Yglesias, Jose, 1952-1961: letters, business card, 31.10.
  - Zazeela, Marian, 1957-1961: extensive correspondence; includes artwork, typescript, notes, theater program, photograph of Zazeela and Rosenthal., 31.11.
  - Zazeela, Marian, 1962-2000: extensive correspondence; includes artwork, manuscript, theater program, flyers, posters., 31.12.
  - Zinn, Marjorie, 1956-1969: postcard, letters, Ebony, March 1956 and Tan, July, 1958, 31.13.
- Series III. MISCELLANEOUS CORRESPONDENCE
  This small series consists of materials that Rosenthal marked as miscellaneous, and mostly contains limited correspondence and ephemera. The letter in the folder titles refers to the first letter of the correspondents' last name.
  - Miscellaneous A, 1953-1961: letters, receipts, artwork, hand-printed booklet, 32.1.
  - Miscellaneous B, ca. 1949-1968: correspondence; includes flyer and postcard, 32.2.
  - Miscellaneous C, ca. 1950-1972: correspondence; includes receipts and Rosenthal's 1966 calendar., 32.3.
  - Miscellaneous D, 1969: letter, 32.4.
  - Miscellaneous G, ca. 1952-1967: letters, postcards, 32.5.
  - Miscellaneous H, ca. 1952-1967: correspondence; includes postcards and invitations., 32.6.
  - Miscellaneous I and J: correspondence; includes greeting card and poster., 32.7.
  - Miscellaneous K, 1952-1970: correspondence; includes greeting card, postcard, photograph of Bonnie Bremser; also Kerista Speeler, vol. 1, issue 3 (1964)., 32.8.
  - Miscellaneous L, 1956-1959: telegram, letter, postcard, 32.9.
  - Miscellaneous M, 1960-1967: letters, postcards, 32.10.
  - Miscellaneous N, 1965-1966: letter, invitation, 32.11.
  - Miscellaneous O, 1958-1959: letters, 32.12.
  - Miscellaneous P, 1955-1960: letters, postcards, manuscript, greeting cards, 32.13.
  - Miscellaneous R, 1957-1967: letters, typescripts, 32.14.
  - Miscellaneous S, 1957-1972: letters, newsletter, drawing, greeting card, 32.15.
  - Miscellaneous T, 1953-1971: ticket for Dylan Thomas reading, letters, 32.16.
  - Miscellaneous W, 1958-1963: letters, greeting card, business card, 32.17.
- Series IV. PROFFESIONAL
  This series contains materials specifically related to Rosenthal's work as an editor, publisher, and writer. It includes correspondence and typescripts from his editorial work at The Chicago Review, Big Table, and other publications. It also contains drafts and proofs of Sheeper, as well as correspondence regarding its publication.
  - Auerhahn Press, 1959-1960: flyer, postcards, 33.1
  - Big Table, 1958-1959, 33.2-33.9.
    - Big Table, 1958-1959: correspondence; includes clipping, poster, and notes., 33.2.
    - Big Table, distribution, 1958-1959: correspondence; includes postcard, invoice, notes, and distribution list., 33.3.
    - Big Table, typescripts, 1959: typescripts for Big Table no. 1; includes typescripts by William Burroughs, Gregory Corso, Jack Kerouac, and Rosenthal (material intended for suppressed 1959 winter edition of The Chicago Review)., 33.4.
    - Big Table; production, 1959: notes, artwork, letter, receipt, 33.5.
    - Big Table, galley proofs, 1959: galley proofs for Big Table no. 1, 33.6.
    - Big Table, Harry Gantt, 1959: correspondence with Harry Gantt, publisher and printer; includes notes, receipt, telegram, and postcards., 33.7.
    - Big Table, ACLU: materials relating to court case over the suppression of Big Table by the US Post Office; includes correspondence, telegram, pamphlet, and copy of judge's decision., 33.8.
    - Big Table, 1959: no. 1, 33.9.
  - Book of Grass, 1967: letters, 33.10.
  - Carp and Whitefish, 1965-1969: correspondence; includes artwork, clipping, invoices, and loose pages and cover of receipt book., 33.11.
  - Chicago Review, 1957-1959, 33.12-34.2
    - Chicago Review, 1957: extensive correspondence; includes notes, manuscripts, typescripts, including typescript for "Invitation to Sleep" by Rosenthal published in The Chicago Review, spring 1957., 33.12.
    - Chicago Review, photographs, 1957: photographs of staff, including Rosenthal; removed from folder # 33.12., 33.13.
    - Chicago Review, 1958-1959: extensive correspondence; includes poster, notes, clippings, and committee report regarding the suppression of The Chicago Review., 33.14.
    - Chicago Review, 1957-1958: vol. 11, no. 1, no. 4, 34.1.
    - Chicago Review, spring 1958, vol. 12, no. 1-3, 34.2.
  - Glamorous Novelties, 1966: notes, typescripts, 34.3
  - Sheeper, 1959-1990, 35.1-38.4.
    - Drafts, 1959-1967: early and rejected drafts; includes manuscripts, typescripts, notebooks. (5 folders), 35.1-35.5.
    - Typescript, 1963: pages 1-80, 35.6.
    - Typescript, 1963: chapters 54, 55, 35.7.
    - Typescript, 1963: sent to Eila Kokkinen from Tangier., 36.1.
    - Typescript, 1963: sent to Michael McClure from Tangier; includes note to McClure., 36.2.
    - Typescript, 1963: first complete typescript (2 folders), 36.3-36.4.
    - Gnaoua, 1964: no. 1; includes passages from Sheeper., 36.5.
    - Grove Press, 1964-1975: extensive correspondence regarding the publication of Sheeper; includes contracts, clippings; also letter from Herbert Huncke and others., 36.6.
    - Typescript, ca. 1965: 68 pages, 36.7.
    - Akzente, 1966: vol. 13, no.6 and special issue; includes chapters from Sheeper., 37.1.
    - Evergreen Review, 1967: vol. 11, no. 46; includes sections from Sheeper., 37.2.
    - Floating Bear Newsletter, 1967: no. 33; includes chapter from Sheeper., 37.3.
    - Growing Hand, 1967: includes chapter from Sheeper, 37.4.
    - Typescript, 1967: final typescript submitted to Grove Press. (2 folders), 37.5-37.6.
    - Les Episodes, 2001: no. 11; includes chapters from Sheeper., 37.7.
    - Galley proofs, 1967: corrected by Rosenthal, Flat Box 38.1.
    - Page proofs, 1967, Flat Box 38.2.
    - Page proofs, 1967: corrected by Rosenthal., Flat Box 38.3.
    - Reviews, 1967-1969: clippings, 37.7.
    - Fan mail and solicitations, 1965-1970: letters, postcards, 37.8.
    - Draft, 1990: copy of first draft of 1990 revision, 37.9.
    - Galley proofs, 1967: revisions by Rosenthal; used as base for 1990 edition., Flat Box 38.4.